《女子监狱》
第二季第五集
他完全不知怎么照顾自己
He had no idea how to take care of himself.
他先用护发素  再用洗发水
He used to condition, then shampoo.
连换尿布都不会
He didn't even know how to change a diaper.
我怎么能把孩子交给这样的人
How could I leave my baby with that?
也许没人教他
Hey, maybe nobody taught him.
也许他是白痴
And maybe he's a dumbass.
错过了她的第一个生日  我很难受
But still, I feel really bad for missing her first birthday.
那可是件大事
It's a big one, you know?
-赶紧  -能让我冲掉吗
- Hurry up. - Can I rinse off?
她们以前会给红妈占一个
They used to hold an empty one for Red.
-滚  到缸子里冲  -疼
- Move it! Do it in the fucking sink. - Ow! That hurts!
谢谢
Gracias.
搞什么
What the f...
天哪
Aw, man!
好了  全都出去  快
All right, everybody out now! Let's go!
听着  西班牙裔区管道出问题了
All right, listen up! We got plumbing issues in Spanish Harlem.
屎都冒出来了  可我们还得干活
Shit's flooded and we gotta get to work.
-所以  -所以他们想插队
- So? - So they wanna cut.
不行  去你妈的
Aw, man! No, fuck that.
还想吃饭吗  想吃就让开
You want breakfast? That's how it is.
搞什么
The fuck?
不好意思  我的姑娘可没说要提供特殊照顾
Excuse me! But my girls are not inclined to offer special privileges.
在我们的浴室里不行
Not in our bathroom.
你的姑娘  什么时候的事
Your girls? When did that happen?
姑娘们  排好队
Ladies? Get on line.
遵命
Yeah.
你违背了我们默认的约定  贱人
You violatin' an unspoken social contract, bitch.
爆你妈的逼  婊子
-你他妈叫我什么  -住手
- What the fuck you call me? - Stop it!
住手  住手
Hey! Cut it out! Cut it out! Settle down!
-怎么回事  -她妈的揍我
- What is going on here? - She fucking punched me.
我可没揍  我就这样推一下
I didn't punch. Man, I pushed her, like this.
-看到了吧  -装吧
- Did you see that? - Dramatic.
-拜托  姐们  -别叫我"姐们"
- Oh, come on, sister! - Don't "sister" me.
-我要给你记一笔  -什么
- I'm writing you a shot. - What?
-长官  这  -拜托
- Officer, please. This... - Come on!
别  这根本就不是她们的浴室
No! This ain't even their bathroom!
怎么  你也想被记一笔
What? You want a shot, too?
别管黑人守卫叫"姐们"
Don't ever call a black guard "sister."
明白吧
You know that.
走
Go.
Get out.
我从你这儿买的蜡烛没用
什么蜡烛
给圣彼得点的蜡烛
你说它能帮我找到工作
我写了申请  放在蜡烛边
蜡烛点了七天
还是没工作
你有再写一个申请
交给某个老板吧
说明书上没写这个
我去跟卢尔德说
好  你去跟卢尔德说
在这等着
弗朗西斯科说你的蜡烛没用
他要洗礼
叫他等等
怎么回事
我不要洗礼  我要我的钱
弗朗西斯科  有势力对你不利
我会帮你的  稍后
打扰了
我在后面装了一个自动关闭的门
你似乎是记不住关门
我特意没关上  方便孩子们上楼
你孩子和附近的任何人都能上去了
这样没关系
我是怕你被抢
来货了  帮我卸一下货好吗
遵命
还要等多久
工作吗  一辈子吧
抱歉  食品券买不到啤酒
Sorry. You can't buy beer with food stamps.
收着
Just take it.
什么
Excuse me?
这是100美元的食品券  快找我50
It's a $100 EBT card. Just give me $50.
拜托  大家都知道你干这勾当
Come on, everybody knows you do this shit.
-算了  -对
- Forget it. - Yeah.
给我滚
Take a hike!
我们可不干这个  你找错店了
We don't do that shit here. You got the wrong store.
Fifty.
减去酒钱
Minus the cost of the beer.
-怎么回事  -什么
你不能那样跟客人说话
你不能拒绝客人  不想做买卖啦
得  你算老几在这教我怎么做生意
你又不是什么有钱的
不许这样跟老子说话
老子拼了命地帮你
把你那群兔崽子当自家的养
你就这样跟我说话
对不起
可以记作战果的女孩必须是自愿
All of the girls must want to have sex.
知道  张  又不是强奸比赛
Yes, Chang, we know. It's not a rape contest.
-什么比赛  -我们在玩上床比赛
- What contest? - We're having a Bang-Off.
必须是在监狱里的
All the girls must be here on camp.
是吗  就是说  我们不能去当地酒吧了
Really? You mean we can't pull from the local bars?
"必须是人"怎么样
Yeah, how about, "All girls must be human"?
大波  这个对你来说应该不是问题吧
Or would that be a problem for you, Boo?
就那么一次
That happened one time.
我们喝醉了
We were drunk.
一定要高潮才算数吗
So, do they have to come for it to count?
问得好
Excellent question.
一定要  有我在  他们肯定高潮
Have to? Son, with me, they always come.
只有一次  太可惜了
Oh, only once? That's so sad.
张  多次高潮能多得几分吗
Hey, Chang, can we get extra points for multiples?
我是超爽女王
I'm the queen of excess.
不行  不能重复得分
No. No double points
但不同的姑娘能得不同的分
but different girls worth different points.
-那是什么  -记分表
- What is that? - Score sheet.
特里姆  6分  查普曼  3分
Trim, six. Chapman, three.
我可不玩  别把我扯进去
I don't wanna play the game. Don't put me in that.
-总共几分  -10
- Three out of what? - Ten.
守卫差不多是10分
Ten's like a guard, right?
1分的就比如那姑娘
And one's like that girl.
我不止3分吧  我可不随便
I am so more than a three. I am not easy.
你不随便  就是放荡而已  确实不同
You're slutty, not easy. There's a difference, semantically.
确实不随便
Yeah, you're not easy.
你只是搞了你的死敌
You only fucked your worst enemy.
那时艾丽克斯不是我的敌人  至少我以为
Alex was not my enemy at the time. That I knew.
这事很复杂
It was complicated.
她对我有种影响力
She has that effect on me.
对我也是  好想干她一干
Me, too. Love to get my dick in her mouth.
也许她能及时赶回来参加比赛呢
Maybe she'll come back in time for the game.
别指望了
Don't count on it.
-玩什么呢  -没什么
- What y'all playing? - Nothing.
老游戏了
A game as old as time.
是吗  叫什么
Oh, yeah? What's it called?
排除
Exclusion.
酷  怎么玩
Cool. How do you play it?
太胡扯了
Man, it's bullshit, man.
我已经因为仓库迟到被记了两次了
I already got two shots for being late to the warehouse.
现在因为怕迟到又被记了一次
And now I got another for trying to keep from being late?
这是我们的浴室
This is our bathroom.
-上次我在这时  -拜托
- When I was here last time... - Oh, God!
听腻了
We've heard.
这要是在以前
That was back in the good ol' days,
你可以趁她睡觉一刀捅了她  没人会说什么
when you could stab a bitch in her sleep and nobody said nothin'.
我说  你想给别人当擦鞋垫吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Do you like being another woman's doormat?
谁说擦鞋垫的事了
Look, who said anything about being a doormat, man?
靠  我是我自己的擦鞋垫
Shit. I'm my own doormat.
哪里的擦鞋垫呢
Yes, but a doormat to where?
我跟你们说
I am telling you,
除非我们现在采取行动  否则就会变成那样
unless we do something now, this is gonna become the way it is.
西班牙裔管事
Spanish running things.
也别指望狱虐锩
And we can't look to the screws for help.
"狱"  这早过时了
"Screws"? Man, you are old.
反正这些姑娘得长点教训
I'm just saying those girls need to learn some manners.
我明白
I know what you sayin'.
是吗
Do you, baby?
叉在左  刀在右
Fork on the left. Knife on the right.
小叉放最左
Little fork on the outer left.
冷死了
It's cold out here.
干活就暖和了
You'll warm up once we get working.
阿尔玛你和费里达除了地上的草
Irma, you and Frieda start pulling weeds out of the floor.
塔斯利兹和吉米还有我  清理垃圾
Taslitz and Jimmy and I will start clearing out this junk.
我不能待很久
Oh, I can't stay long.
-杰克今晚要带我去看电影  -行
- Jack is taking me to the movies tonight. - Okay.
我们得早点去  复活节游行肯定很多人排队
We need to get there early. There'll be a huge line for Easter Parade.
吉米  那你就去除草吧
Jimmy, maybe you help pull weeds?
好  但我一会儿就得走了
All right. But I have to go soon.
姐们  来帮我一把
Girls, give me a hand with this, huh?
怎么
What?
你说温室俱乐部叫人放松
You said this greenhouse club would be relaxing.
可以让我们远离喧嚣
Give us time away from the noise.
可没说要搬木头
You didn't say nothing about hauling wood.
你还要不要取暖了
You wanna get warm or not?
-女士们早  -海利先生早
- Morning, ladies. - Morning, Mr. Healy.
是杰克吗
Is that Jack?
红妈  你给自己找了点挑战啊
Quite a little challenge you've set for yourself, Red.
是  我也感觉到了
Yes, I'm getting that feeling.
女士们  不介意我跟红妈聊两句吧
Ladies, would you mind if I spoke to Red for a minute?
不碍事  我们去除草
Uh, not at all. We'll go help pulling weeds.
今晚他们要在利奇菲尔德高中
So, they're putting up a production of Our Town
演《我们的镇子》
at Litchfield High tonight.
你说叫卡佳去看看好不好呢
Do you think maybe that'd be a good thing to take Katya to see?
不知道
I don't know.
我不太熟悉那所高中的演员
I'm not familiar with the actors at that particular high school.
我觉得接触点文化或许是好事
I thought maybe a little culture would be nice.
其实  我只是想今晚能摆脱她老妈
Mostly, I just wanna get away from her mother for the evening.
要不就去吃个饭
Or we could just go to dinner.
刚开了家意大利餐厅  你看行吗
They just opened an Italian place. What do you think?
海利
Healy,
我管厨房的时候我们说好了的
we had an agreement back when I ran the kitchen.
你给我抓背  我告诉你什么时候该修耳毛
You scratched my back, and I told you when it was time to trim your ear hairs.
如今我的背不用抓了
But I don't need my back scratched anymore
也就不想再有瓜葛了
and I'd rather be left alone.
我只是问问你的意见
I'm just asking your opinion.
别看戏了  带她去吃饭吧
Skip the play. Take her to dinner.
意大利餐厅
Italian?
什么  浪漫印度菜  拜托
What, romantic Indian? Come on.
好吧  谢谢
All right. Thank you.
海利  能装个取暖器吗
Hey, Healy, can we get a space heater in here?
我看看吧
I'll look into it.
估计不行
Probably not.
舔屎精
Shit licker.
能种大麻吗
Can we grow pot?
听表亲说拐角那栋房子
So I heard from my cousin that the whole front of the
前面全垮了  垮在人行道上了
building on the corner fell off and crashed onto the sidewalk?
没错
Yeah. Boom.
看这张反自杀海报
Check out the anti-suicide poster.
你说  会有人想在这地方自杀吗
You think someone tried to do it in, like, right in here?
-也许就在你坐的这个位置上  -卡尔
- Maybe right where you're sitting? - Oh, Cal!
怎么了  问问而已
What? It's just a question.
帕波  太好了
Oh, Piper! Oh, what a relief.
怎么了
What?
她怕你不如以前漂亮了呢
Oh. She was worried that you wouldn't be pretty anymore.
说了  她打赢了
I told you. She won the fight.
没错  打得屁滚尿流
That's right. I kicked ass.
我在单独拘禁室里蹲了三个星期
I spent three weeks in solitary confinement
满脑子想着"大赢家"
just thinking, "Winner!"
帕波  莱瑞来看过你吗
Oh, Piper. Did Larry come to visit you?
没有  他不会来看我了
No. And he won't be coming to visit me.
说了  我们分了
I told you. We broke up.
他的收入潜力真叫人怀疑
Well, his earning potential was questionable.
我还以为你会留个大疤呢
I was hoping that you would have, like, a gnarly scar.
增加个性和神秘感
Add character and mystery.
还有时间
There's still time.
你能另寻佳偶的  我可以帮你
You'll find another man. I can help you.
-没必要了  -我想帮你
- There's no need for that. - No, I want to.
内莉不是要来吗
Wasn't Neri supposed to come?
是的  但她进不来
Yes. They wouldn't let her in.
她背景核查时出了点问题  这会儿在大厅呢
There was some issue with her background check. She's in the lobby.
我跟你说  我最烦的
I tell you what I find most disturbing
就是这儿跟我的高中可像了
is that it looks almost exactly like my old high school in here.
一样的煤渣砖墙
Same cinder block construction,
低低的天花板  昏暗的灯光
low ceilings, oppressive fluorescent lighting.
我怀疑是故意的  也算是个惩罚吧
I wonder if that's intentional. Like part of the punishment?
如果真是这样  政府真是好样的
If so, kudos to the government,
太有才了
because it's genius.
爸爸呢
And where's Daddy?
他不想见我吗
He didn't wanna see me?
他当然想见你了  有事耽搁了
Of course he did, darling. Something came up.
没什么事  你不用骗我
Nothing came up. You don't have to lie to me.
他不想在这见到我
He doesn't wanna see me in here.
-对  -卡尔  不对
- That's right. - No, Cal. That is not right.
你不能让她这么想
You can't let her think that.
-总比那样好  -不
- Well, it's better than the other thing. - No.
-哪样  -没什么
- What other thing? - It's nothing.
既然没什么  那就跟我说说吧  卡尔
Well, then if it's nothing, can you at least tell me what it is? Cal?
我们说好了不告诉你的
We agreed that we shouldn't tell you.
不过你可以猜
But you can guess.
不是吧  坏消息
Oh, no. Is it bad?
够了  卡尔  这不合适
Oh, stop it, Cal. This is not appropriate.
什么不合适
What is not appropriate?
我是个蹲监狱的成年人  我能接受的
I am an adult who is in prison! I can handle things.
快跟我说说怎么回事  天哪
You have to tell me what it is. God damn it!
爸爸失业了
Did Daddy lose his job?
-你房子烧了  -没有
- Did your house burn down? - No.
我房子烧了
Did my house burn down?
没有  亲爱的  不是财产的事
No, darling, it isn't property.
别提示
No hints, please.
-人的事  -对
- So it's a person? - Yeah.
爸爸病了  死了  爸爸死了
Is Daddy sick? Dead? Is Daddy dead?
亲爱的  爸爸没事
Darling, Daddy is fine.
就是胆固醇有点问题  不过他用鱼肝油就好
Aside from his cholesterol, but he's taking fish oil for that.
继续  接近了  爸爸没事  不过
Keep going. You're getting warmer. Daddy's fine, but...
丹尼  波丽  莱瑞  奶奶
Danny? Polly? Larry? Grandmother!
奶奶死了  快死了  奶奶快死了
Grandmother's dead! Grand... Dying! Grandmother's dying!
对  奶奶快死了
Yes! Grandmother's dying!
奶奶快死了
Grandmother's dying!
不
Oh, no.
天哪
Oh, my God.
曼多萨  你的人不能使用B区的浴室
Mendoza, your people are not authorized to use the B-Dorm bathroom.
你们自己有浴室
You have your own bathroom.
那种屎花满池的地方也叫浴室
Is that what you call that place with the fountains of caca?
-我会叫水管工来的  -什么时候
- I'm getting a plumber. - When?
等菲格从奥尔巴尼回来给我批准
When I get authorization from Fig when she gets back from Albany.
难道你不觉得
Well, in the meantime,
在此期间厨房的伙计们要找个地方洗澡吗
don't you think your kitchen workers should have a sanitary place to go?
尤其她们是给你切三明治的人
Especially since they're the ones taking the crust off your sandwiches?
你问都没问  就直接闯进去了
You didn't even ask. You just stormed in.
卡普托先生
Mr. Caputo,
我的人能使用B区的浴室吗  拜托了
can my people use the B-Dorm bathroom? Please?
可以  你们暂时可以共用
Fine. You can share it. For now.
多谢  对了  我办公室能要根蜡烛吗
Thank you. By the way, can I have a candle for my office?
你想点蜡烛
You wanna light a candle,
礼拜天去教堂要吧  用电力的吧
go to church on Sunday, use one of the electric ones.
别太自大了  曼多萨
Don't get cocky with me, Mendoza.
你是很重要  但并非不可替代  给我记住
You're important, but you're replaceable. Don't forget that.
报警
让那混蛋被遣送回去
不  不要报警
报警只会惹来麻烦
那这叫什么  永恒的幸福
替孩子们想象
他不会伤害他们的
阿图罗对他们一直很好
可他对你不好
你希望他们长大后也觉得可以这么对女人吗
歌洛丽娅
离我远点
我只想谈谈
求你了
对不起
你聋了还是怎么
她不想跟你说话  狗娘养的
歌洛丽娅  求你了
我知道我不对  我会改的
边下地狱边改吧
阿图罗
本尼托  胡里奥
给我过来
弗洛利西塔
给你一分钟
我不知道我怎么了  不知道
但我离不开你  歌洛丽娅
求你了
拜托  阿图罗
他必将佑你
不入捕鸟之陷阱  不染致命之瘟疫
他的羽翼为你遮挡  他的雄翅为你庇护
他的忠诚便是你的盾牌和壁垒
你在为你祈祷呀  阿姨
Who are you praying for, t?a?
你妈妈
Tu mama.
格鲁伯出局了
Gruber's out of play.
谁是格鲁伯
Who's Gruber? Oh!
前额暴突满脸雀斑那个
Like the freckly girl with the giant forehead?
在木棚那  环形锯后面
In the woodshed. Behind the band saw.
其他人都在做架子  我们做"爱"
Everybody else was making a shelf, and we were making L-O-V-E.
不知道你说的是不是"恶心"
Oh, yeah. Well, I'm not sure that's how you spell "gross."
不过还是恭喜你  大波
But congratulations, Boo.
给自己找了个1分妹
You got yourself a one-pointer.
一波在手  胜过二波在林
Boob in the hand is worth two in the bush.
没错  也就那个林算分
Yeah, well, it's only the bush that counts.
不过  继续加油
But, hey! Keep it up.
在低自尊城还有好多五分钱呢
There's plenty of other nickel slots in Low Self Esteem City.
你想要我  我只在单独桌上玩大票子
You want me, I'll be playing for big money at a private table.
你的意思是跟自己玩吧
Well, by that, you must mean playing with yourself,
因为我可没见你跟谁玩
'cause I don't see you playing with anybody else.
不信
Oh, no?
费歇尔长官
Hey, Officer Fischer?
能劳烦你帮我把电视声音调大一点吗
Hey, would you mind turning the volume up for me on the television?
声音有点小了
It's just that it's kind of low.
行  尼古拉斯
Sure, Nichols.
多谢
Hey, thanks.
你今天可真漂亮
Hey, you look lovely today, by the way.
过奖了
Well, thank you.
哪里
Sure.
明白了吧  我没兴趣
See, I'm not interested
玩汗津津的阴道接力赛
in running some sweaty fallopian relay race.
我把这当作艺术
I look at this like an art form.
你别做梦了
You're out of your depth.
对我而言  没什么不可能
My depth has no depth.
我是性方面的史蒂夫・乔布斯  那女人是10分
I am a sexual Steve Jobs. And that bitch is worth 10 points.
我在意大利餐厅订了个位
But I made reservations at the Spaghetti Factory.
你应该先问问我的  我已经跟乌利亚约好了
You should have asked me. I made plans with Ulya.
那就劳烦你跟她重新约一下吧
Well, I'd really appreciate it if you could reschedule.
什么
What?
重新约一下
不  我可不想
为什么
我们可以其他时候去
他也可以其他时候去
他要我在这待一整天等他吗
两周前  他说我们会去纽约
可结果根本没去
他想什么时候改计划就什么时候改  甚至不允许我有计划
能说英语吗
Can you please speak English?
为什么要我们说英语  为什么你不说俄语
Why we speak English? Why not you speak Russian?
为什么  因为你们现在住在美国
Why? Because you live in America now!
我们俩一起做点开心的事
And I don't think it's so horrible for me to want to
就这么糟糕吗
do something nice together!
你每天都能见到乌利亚
You can see Ulya any day of the week.
你又不用去工作
It's not like you have to go to a job or anything!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不是故意发脾气的
I didn't mean to lose my temper.
我很期待见到你
也许我们可以一起出去
Maybe we could all go out some place together.
要是你们不喜欢吃东西  我们就去看戏吧
Or if you don't feel like eating, we can go see a play.
我想跟我朋友在一起
I want to spend time with my friend.
行  所以我说乌利亚也可以来
Right. Which is why I said Ulya's welcome to come.
你朋友就是我朋友
我朋友就是你朋友
你没有朋友  山姆
You don't have any friends, Sam.
黑人区的水压好多了
Yo, the water pressure is so much better in the ghetto.
我知道
I know, right?
真操蛋
It's fucked up.
感觉她们享受特别待遇
It's like they're getting special privileges
我们倒像黑人了
and we're the black people.
等等  老子的鞋呢
Hey, wait. Where the fuck are my shoes?
老子的鞋呢
Where are my fucking shoes?
在我床上
This was in my bed.
姑娘们  赶紧得哦
Hey, ladies, you better get to moving.
要不然  就要迟到啦
If you don't hurry, you gonna be late for work.
快
Gank!
妈的  行
Oh, fuck. It's on.
有人在搅事
Somebody start untangling this shit.
你怎么了
What's the matter with you?
没事
Nothing.
我奶奶病了
My grandmother is sick.
还以为是我抓到你看黄色照片了呢
I thought maybe I caught you with a porn.
奶奶生病了不用这么羞愧
A sick babushka is nothing to be ashamed of.
我不想让我的事烦到别人
I don't wanna bore anyone with my problems.
别人的事都是烦人的事
All problems are boring until they're your own.
清人
Count time.
列队清人
You must stand at count.
重复  请大家列队清点人数
Repeat, you must stand at count under code 320.
怎么了
What happened?
她在水池里转身的时候把脚崴了
She scraped her foot turning laps in the pool.
脚伤一直没好  她就去看医生
When it wasn't healing, she went in to see the doctor
结果发现她肾脏功能衰竭了
and it turns out her kidney levels were off the charts.
他们给她做了透析  她被感染了
So they put her on dialysis, and then she got an infection.
就是这样的
That's how it happens.
一触即发  好比内脏多米诺骨牌
It all goes at once. Like internal organ dominoes.
抱歉  估计你不想听到这话
I'm sorry. That's probably not what you want to hear.
没事  我又不是来找安慰的
It's all right. I'm not looking for sympathy.
我其实在学你的样子
I'm trying to follow your lead, actually.
坚强点  不作声色
Be strong. Suffer in silence.
不作声好
I like the silent part.
也许她能渡过难关
She might pull through.
那句话怎么说来着
Anyhow, what is it that they say?
握得越紧  放得越轻
Hang on tightly, let go lightly.
什么
What?
这是克里夫・欧文在电影《杀戮赌场》里说的
It's something that Clive Owen says in the movie Croupier.
这样安慰一点吗
Is it supposed to be comforting?
要是克里夫・欧文在这儿说也许我会安慰一点
It probably would be comforting if Clive Owen were here to say it.
克里夫・欧文个鬼  永远别放手
Fuck Clive Owen. Don't ever let go.
除非他们逼你
Not until they make you.
这间浴室所有的水
All the water from this bathroom
都从这个地板的这根管子里出
goes out this pipe under the floor here.
把它清理干净之前  就一直会有污水和臭气
Until it's cleared, you're gonna have all of the water and effluvia.
每洗一次澡  污水就会从管子里冒出来一次
It's gonna be comin' out of the pipe every time you have the showers going.
为什么  究竟怎么回事
Well, why? What's the actual problem?
要看情况  蛇不大可能够得到这儿  所以
Depends. The snake's not long enough to reach it, so...
也许是树根
It's probably roots.
卡普托先生  能聊两句吗
Mr. Caputo, may I speak to you for a moment?
你觉得你这是在干什么
What the hell do you think you're doing?
我可没有签字同意外面的人进来
I didn't sign off on an outside contractor.
在您决定昨天或者今早
I made an executive decision
不来上班之后  我做出了这个行政决定
when you decided not to come to work yesterday or this morning.
我要去一个新闻发布会
I had a press conference.
我丈夫正在竞选州参议员
My husband is running for state Senate.
这是杰里米
Well, this is Jeremy.
他正在竞选我们工作地的监狱水管工
He's running for Plumber of the Prison, where we work.
我们有学过疏通管道的狱警
There's a CO trained in plumbing.
是卡纳里克  他已经来过了
His name is Kanarick. He's been here already.
然后呢
And?
说实话  这个通不了
To be honest, this isn't gonna get unclogged.
外面整个管道都要挖出来
You're gonna have to remove the whole exit pipe.
那要花多少钱
How much is that gonna cost?
管子是嵌进混泥土里的
Okay, it's embedded in the concrete,
所以我要找个手提钻
so I gotta get a jackhammer,
还要叫我的管道维修团队来
I gotta get my pipe fitting crews in here.
多少钱
How much?
最少8万
80 grand, minimum.
我的老天爷  没有别的办法了
Jesus Christ on a crutch. And there's no other alternative?
也可以叫姑娘们洗澡的时候快点
You can always have the girls take shorter showers.
这好像是个比较合理的解决方案
Well, that seems like a reasonable solution.
这可不是解决方案  只是权宜之计罢了
Solution? That's not a solution. It's a bullshit stopgap.
-这个必须换掉  -会换的
- This needs to be addressed. - And it will be.
可眼下我们严重赤字
But we are dealing with a very serious deficit at the moment!
你知道的
As you know.
还有  我们对供应商也有明确规定
Besides, there is an approved list of vendors that we work with.
事关安全  你明白的
It's a security issue. You understand.
该死  为什么要修管道
Shit, why fix the plumbing at all?
别给她们吃不就得了
Let's just cut their food rations
她们就不会拉这么多了
so they don't shit as much.
我先去查人  一会跟你讨论这个问题
I will crunch the numbers and get back to you on that.
把我叫过来的钱谁给
Hey, who's gonna pay me for coming out here?
-查普曼  -能跟你聊两句吗
- Chapman. - Can I talk to you for a minute?
可以  关门
Sure. Close the door.
看到你没事就好
Glad to see you're looking well.
是吗
Are you?
-什么  -没什么  多谢
- Excuse me? - Nothing. Thank you.
怎么了
What can I do for you?
我奶奶病得很重
My grandmother is very ill.
太不幸了
I'm sorry to hear that.
我知道你不会因这种事同意准假
I know that you probably don't grant furlough for things like this.
哪怕你会  估计也轮不到我
And even if you did, I don't expect you would ever give it to me.
但我要是连问都不问  我是不会安生的
But I could not live with myself if I did not at least ask.
你能批我准假去看我奶奶吗
Could you please give me furlough to see my grandmother?
准假
Furlough?
准假就像尼斯湖水怪
Furlough is like the Loch Ness Monster.
经常说起  却很少见
Much discussed and rarely seen.
难道你连申请的权力都没有吗
But don't you have the power to at least apply?
抱歉  恕我无能为力
I'm sorry. There's nothing I can do to help you.
还有事吗
Is there something else?
没有了
No. No. That's it.
-你就冷眼旁观  -什么
- You just stood there. - What?
你冷眼旁观
You stood there...
看着她袭击我
while she attacked me!
然后又给了她新牙
And then you gave her new teeth.
事发时我不在附近
I was nowhere near the incident,
德盖特可以给我作证
as Doggett will corroborate, I assure you.
我知道我越界了
I know that I overstepped my bounds,
但我可能会被杀
but I could've been killed!
要是我能干预  我肯定会干预的
Were I there to intervene, I most certainly would have.
你奶奶的事真是不幸  谢谢你来访
I'm sorry about your grandmother. Thanks for stopping by.
什么意思  他放弃了  因为黑色稻草人
What do you mean? He's quitting? Because of the Black Scarecrow?
黑色稻草人根本不和他一个重量级别
The Black Scarecrow isn't even in his weight class,
就算是一样的  他也有弱点啊
and even if he was, he has a weakness.
他有弱点啊
He has a weakness...
你觉得这次是什么
What is it this time, you think?
不知道  我试着不去听
I don't know. I try not to listen.
行了  好奇也没什么
Ah, come on, there's no shame in being curious.
我不想别人觉得
I wouldn't want people thinking
我多管闲事
I'm sticking my nose where it doesn't belong.
可她也许遇到麻烦了
Yeah, but she could be in trouble.
黑色稻草人也许
Hey, the Black Scarecrow could be
准备敲诈她之类的
trying to extort her for money or something.
不  黑色稻草人是个摔跤手
No, the Black Scarecrow's a wrestler.
他本该和她儿子比赛的  但他临阵逃脱了
He was supposed to wrestle her son, but he's chickening out.
还以为你没听呢
I thought you didn't listen.
我忍不住
I couldn't help it.
她一边哭一边说摔跤的事
She was talking about wrestling while crying!
那也不能说明什么
It doesn't take much.
我有次还看到她一边看加菲猫漫画一边哭呢
I once saw her crying reading a Garfield comic.
我到希望能不打扰她的隐私
I wish I could give her her privacy,
可我要在这站岗
but it's my job to stand here.
没事  也不是所有人都要隐私
It's fine. I mean, not everybody wants their privacy.
我就不要
I know I don't.
是吗
Yeah?
是的  我喜欢私密  但不喜欢一个人私密
Yeah, well, you know, I like privacy, but not alone privacy.
我听不太明白
I'm not sure what that means.
我的意思是我管电
It means I work in electrical,
所以我知道哪里的摄像头坏了
so I know all the spots where the cameras don't work.
如果你对其他事情好奇
You know, if you're ever feeling curious about other things.
你要打电话吗  如果不要  请离开
Do you have a phone call to make? Because if not, I suggest you move on.
-费歇尔  -赶紧的  犯人
- Hey, now, Fischer... - Now, inmate!
行
All right. Jeez.
如果他带了自己的椅子  肯定能打败他
But if he brings his own chair, he can really hurt him.
他能赢的
He can win!
也能给我们家带来荣耀
And return glory to our family.
-天哪  -怎么了
- Oh, man! - What is it?
盐  她们动了手脚  辣椒婊子们
Salt. They gave us special trays. Chili shittin' bitches!
靠  她们故意这样的  她们知道
Man! They fuckin' with us this way 'cause they know
我们黑人血压容易高
our people's predisposition for hypertension.
天哪  她们想杀人
Man, they tryin' to kill us.
你们还想怎样  别惹厨子
Well, what do y'all expect? Don't fuck with the cooks.
什么
What?
怎么我也中了  我什么都没做
Hey! Why I got it like that? I didn't even do nothing.
她们把我们算成一伙的了
They're grouping us all together!
这叫种族主义  笨鸟
It's called racism, slow bird.
你是刚生出来还是怎么的
What, was you just born or something?
闭嘴
Shut up!
诀窍在于假装盐是糖
The secret is pretend the salt is sugar.
本尼特  我有个问题
So, Bennett, I got a question.
你是愿意住在一间地基破裂的房子里呢
Would you rather live in a house with a cracked foundation
还是愿意住在一个从不熄灯的停车场对面
or one across from a parking lot where the lights never go off?
都不想住
Neither.
可要是你的钱不够买别的房子了呢
But what if nothing else is in your price range?
我要个换一盘菜
Hey! I want a new tray.
不好意思  拿到什么是什么
Sorry. You get what you get.
胡说  你别想乱弄我的菜
Bullshit! You can't mess with my food!
我他妈又没搅和
I wasn't part of that shit!
珍娜  冷静
Janae, calm down.
说你呢
Inmate. Hey!
不能这样
You cannot do that!
靠
Fuck!
-放开我  -闭嘴
- Get off me! - Shut up!
-你没事吧  -没事
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
把他弄开
Get him off me!
-你想关禁闭吗  -不想
- You wanna go down the hill? - No.
那就别再这样搞
Then you cut that shit out.
扣你一个月的粮饷
You just lost commissary for a month, inmate.
你想到对策了还是就想这样
You got a plan or are you only trying to start shit?
我会处理的
I'm handling it.
那最好  里面可是我的外孙女
You better. That's my granddaughter in there.
怎么了  还以为你们出去了
-他打了他  他打了本尼托  -报警
-不  -不  弗洛利西塔
他会找到我们的  他会杀了我的  我们得离开这
我有钱
我们去佛罗里达跟弗兰基和丽塔住
你怎么弄到的
食品券的钱  我一直在存
我买下食品券  然后什么也没卖就跟政府要钱
卢尔德  你觉得靠买蜡烛和草药我就能活吗
歌洛丽娅  对不起
他挡我路了
是吗  你冲着谁去的  狗娘养的
歌洛丽娅  我真的想跟你单独谈谈
不行  你这贱逼少来烦她
不管你的事
你他妈怎么把蜡烛丢在地板上
我供养众神
好让他们将你带回圣多明哥呢  混蛋
对墨西哥人才这么叫混蛋  我是多明尼加人
这是愤怒之言  不用你纠正  只是为了表示痛恨
你报警了吗
你想我被驱逐出境
我没有  卢尔德
好歹我替你照顾了孩子
我告诉你  我会杀了你的  杀了你们俩
快  他往后面走了
-歌洛丽娅・曼多萨  -是
- Gloria Mendoza? - Yeah.
-这是你的店  -是
- This is your business? - Yeah.
曼多萨小姐  我有你的逮捕令
Miss Mendoza, I have a warrant for your arrest.
罪名是诈骗
You're under arrest for fraud.
-什么  -手放到后面
- What? - Put your hands behind your back.
他要从后面逃走了
带她走
Get her out of here.
别浪费钱保释
替我照顾好他们
会没事的  弗洛利西塔  他们不会让当妈妈的坐牢的
会没事的
我会点蜡祈求圣芭芭拉为此惩罚你的
蜡烛最好是去别处买  你们家的屁用都没有
吃屎去吧
一杯白的一杯啤的
Give me a shot and a beer.
10块钱
It's $10.
好  谢谢  谢谢大家
All right. Thank you. Thank you.
鼓手加布・隆尼
We've got Gabe Ronley on drums.
贝斯手乔・卡普托
Got Joe Caputo on bass.
吉他手约翰・格里克曼
John Glickman on guitar.
我是阿尔伯特・罗斯  我们是副乳
I'm Albert Roth and we are Side Boob.
接下来的歌叫《巫师》
This next song is called The Sorcerers.
也叫《约翰・格里克曼是恋童癖》
Otherwise known as John Glickman is a Pedophile.
同样的罪  我们却要比白人多坐20%的牢
We go to prison 20% longer for the same crimes as white people.
他们随时可以把我们叫住开始盘查
They can stop and frisk us whenever they want,
现在呢  那些贱货在我的菜里做了手脚
and now, when some bitch fucks with our food,
却要把我摁在地上
I'm the one who gets thrown on the ground?
这不对
This shit ain't right.
还有  还扣了你的粮饷
And don't forget they took your commissary.
愤怒吧  全都愤怒起来
Be angry. Y'all need to be angry.
我还想叫大家绝食抗议呢
Man, I would say we go on hunger strike,
可现在已经这样了
but that shit's already happening.
贱人
Yo, tortilla chick!
看来有人拐错弯了
Look like somebody took a wrong turn on the way to the barrio.
你跟我来浴室
You and me in the bathroom, now.
-我跟你去  -我去
- I'll come with you. - I got this.
不  她不该单独去
No, she shouldn't go alone.
没事的  冷静
No, she'll be fine. Heel.
我打赌我们的姑娘随便就能搞定那贱货
Yeah, I put money on our girl over that beanbag bitch any day.
说不好  曼多萨会可可果巫术
I don't know, man. Mendoza be on that coconut magic.
她就像个巫婆
She's like a bruja and shit.
我让她看看什么是可可果巫术
I'll show her some coconut magic.
把可可果放在我的袜子里
Put a coconut in my sock. Wham!
打不死她  贱人
Sock a nut, bitch!
说着玩呢
I'm just playing.
你真该去开个专栏
You must got some real big feet.
这乐队最诺母
The fucking best song in this fucking band...
想知道是什么吗
You wanna know what it is?
是关于在他妈的矿厂里干活的家伙的
Is the one with the guys working in the fucking mine.
那首歌他妈的就像他妈的经典歌
That fucking song is like a classic fucking song.
那首歌他妈的
That fucking song
是他妈的收音机里听到的歌
is a song you hear on the fucking radio.
其实呢  那首歌不是关于矿工的
Actually, that song is not about workers in the mine.
-什么意思  -是个比喻
- What do you mean? - No, it's a metaphor.
阿尔写的是他结扎解除的事
Al wrote it about his vasectomy reversal.
-不是吧  -真的
- No shit! - Seriously.
你们有CD吗  有的话一定要告诉我
Hey, you guys got a CD? Please tell me you got a fucking CD.
瞧这个
Look at this.
你希望谁当选参议员呢
What do you look for in a state senator?
-菲格先生  -菲格先生
- Mr. Fig. - Mr. Fig.
"之所以只有我一个人戴头盔"
"Look, the reason I'm the only one with a helmet
"是因为我比你有钱"
"is 'cause I'm richer than you."
"锤钉子可真难  我都累死了"
"Hammering that nail was hard. I'm pooped."
她出现了
There she is.
每个强势男人背后都有一个欠操样的强势巫婆
Behind every strong man is a strong, cunt-faced witch monster.
开始工作吧
Let's get to work!
"开始工作吧"
"Let's get to work."
我问问你
Let me ask you something.
一开始的时候菲格不在吧
When you first started, Fig wasn't there, right?
你直接跟监狱长说话吧
You talked directly to the warden?
没错  特别好
Yeah. It was great.
他当时早就吓死了
Actually, he was fucking terrifying.
但至少你跟他说话的时候
But at least when you talked to him,
是在跟一个男人说话
you were talking to a guy.
我讨厌跟女人聊女人的问题
I hate talking about women's issues to women.
很恐怖
It's creepy.
你跟他说的时候  他在不在乎
When you talked to him, did he give a shit?
因为我会很乐意向一个
Because I would really like to report to someone
在乎这事的人汇报
who I felt gave a shit
我们应该照顾好这些姑娘的
about these women we're meant to be taking care of.
-要纸巾吗  -我不要什么狗屁纸巾
- You want a tissue? - No, I don't want a fucking tissue.
-我说真的  -是吗
- I'm serious. - Yeah?
好吧
All right.
你看看我们今年有多操蛋
I mean, think about the fucked up year we're having.
多么落魄
We are failing here.
我他妈连修厕所的事都得不到批准
I can't even get approval to fix the fucking toilets.
-不好意思  -没事
- I'm sorry, man. - That's all right.
至少我们应该
I mean, the least we should do
保证这些女人的安全和干净
is keep these women safe and clean.
没错
You know, you're right.
You're right.
-至少要干净  -至少要干净
- At least clean. - At least clean.
至少厨房里的人要干净
At least the women in the kitchen.
至少他妈的要保证厨房里的人干净
At least those women in the kitchen. Keep 'em fucking clean.
他妈的要保证她们干净
Fuckin' A. Keep them fucking clean.
歌洛丽娅  我希望我们能做朋友
Gloria, I was hoping that we could be friends.
你想跟我过不去  你不想吧
You wanna fuck with me? You don't wanna fuck with me.
我给你烟了
I gave you cigarettes.
我也给你蛋糕了
And I gave you cake.
可这不意味着我们就是朋友了
But that don't mean that we're friends.
并且那些烟  他妈的都老了
And those cigarettes? They were fucking stale.
我们能不能好好谈谈
Listen, can we just talk about this like responsible...
不能  我没在跟你谈  我是在告诉你
No, no, no, no, no. I'm not talking to you. I'm telling you.
要是你的姑娘再敢碰我的
If any of your girls touches any of mine,
就不是菜里放盐这么简单了
there's gonna be more than salt in your food next time.
-歌洛丽娅  -明白了吗
- Gloria... - You understand me?
歌洛丽娅  我不想跟你过不去
Gloria, I don't want any trouble with you.
我一直在跟她们说
I've been telling them,
"我们去用西班牙区的浴室吧"
"Let's just go use the Spanish bathroom."
苏珊娜可以清理干净  她会乐意的
Suzanne can clean it. And then she'll like that.
你和你的姑娘就可以用黑人区的浴室了
And then you and your girls could just take the ghetto bathroom.
我站你这边
I'm on your side.
你们准备给我们用浴室
Oh, you were gonna give us the bathroom?
胡扯  你有什么浴室可以给我们
Bullshit, mama! Because you? You don't got no bathroom to give.
拜托  这又怎么了
Oh, no, man. What the fuck is wrong with you?
我年纪大了
I'm too old for this shit.
我年纪太大了  这就是我的问题
I'm just too old for this shit. That's what's wrong with me!
我根本都不了解这些姑娘
Listen, hey, I don't even know these girls, okay?
是她们要我来当什么干妈的
And they want me to be some kind of den mother, right?
我努力配合你
And I'm trying to work with you
可你却一个劲地针对我
and all you're trying to do is run over me.
我想办法给你浴室  行吗  我好说话
I'm trying to give you the bathroom, okay? I'm a good talker...
可我不能白给啊
but I can't sell this shit unless you give me something.
-你也得给点什么  -给什么
- You gotta give me something. - Like what?
美味和沃森一直说
Taystee and Watson have been talking about
想转移到保管处去
wanting to get transferred to custodial.
-保管处  -对
- Custodial? - Yeah.
她们想跟那个辛迪一起  我是说
They wanna be with their girl, that girl Cindy. I mean, you...
那里有两个西班牙裔姑娘
There're a couple of Spanish girls in custodial.
也许你可以跟卡普托说说
Maybe you could talk to Caputo and, you know,
把她们转到厨房去
have them transferred to the kitchen.
这样我就能想办法了
Maybe I could work with that.
怎样
Huh?
拜托
Oh, fuck, come on, man.
行
Fine.
你先证明你会清理浴室
Show me you could clear the bathroom,
然后我就去和卡普托说
and then I'll talk to Caputo.
你自己也振作点  我他妈都没揍你
And get yourself together 'cause, Jesus, I didn't even fucking hit you.
海利先生  你要见我
Mr. Healy, you wanted to see me?
关门
Door.
我在给你申请三天的准假
I'm submitting you for a three-day furlough.
不保证一定会批  但我会尽力而为
There are no guarantees, but I'm gonna do my best to try to push it forward.
你是要住未婚夫那儿吧
I'm assuming that you're gonna be staying with your fianc?.
我得把地址写下
I need to write down an address.
行  好
Yes. Of course.
你要给他打电话确认一下吗
Would you like to call him to make sure?
我马上就去
I'll call right away.
谢谢你  海利先生
Thank you, Mr. Healy.
至少该试一试
I think it's only fair we give it a shot.
这是我该做的
It's the least we can do.
查普曼
And, Chapman.
你是我的责任
I'm responsible for you.
乔
Hey! Joe!
早  海利
What's up, Healy?
昨晚我可高兴了  你们真棒
I had a lot of fun last night. You guys were amazing.
谢谢捧场
Right, thanks for coming out.
这个工作转移  请你签字
I need you to sign this work transfer.
有两个姑娘从保管处转移
I'm moving a couple of girls from custodial.
弗洛雷斯和桑切斯
Flores and Sanchez.
行  那样保管处不会缺人吗
Okay. But won't that leave custodial shorthanded?
会再找人  曼多萨要人到厨房帮忙
Yeah, we'll figure that out. Mendoza needs help in the kitchen.
行
Okay.
我已经开始期待下周二了
I'm already looking forward to next Tuesday.
-好  -副乳周二会
- Right. - Side Boob Tuesdays.
-多谢  -见到你很高兴  卡普多
- Thanks, Healy. - Good seeing you, Capu dawg.
张  你核实过吗
Chang, are you confirming these bangs,
还是就相她一句话了
or are you just taking her word for it?
我不管你们  我只管记数
I don't smell fingers. I just write numbers.
她已经5分了  你零蛋
She got five points. You, zilcho.
行  已经三天了
All right, it's been three days.
除非她能无性繁殖  但那几乎不可能
I mean, unless she's cloning herself, that seems highly unlikely.
游戏而已  尼古拉斯
It's just a game, Nichols.
那要公平竞争才叫游戏啊
Yeah, but it's not a game unless it's being played fairly.
什么味
What's that smell?
尼古拉斯  你换香水了
Nichols, you got a new fragrance?
没错  是不顾一切味
Oh, yeah, it's desperation.
你还是洗干净吧  姑娘闻了就掉头了
You might wanna wash because girls turn right off when they smell that.
我这手指闻起来像个破网球
My finger smells like an old tennis ball.
操蛋  在骚逼长官身上浪费了两天
God, I screwed myself. I mean, two days I wasted on Officer Twat Tease.
-你目标太高了  -我太自大了
- You were too ambitious. - I was arrogant.
傲慢自大
It's a classic story of hubris.
我就像还没操到太阳手指就融化掉的伊卡洛斯
I'm like Icarus whose wings melted before he could fuck the sun.
你可以跟别人说她有疱疹
You could always tell people she got herpes.
这样不错吧
It's good, isn't it? Eh?
大家总是不记得我喜欢恶作剧
People always forget to remember I'm tricksy, huh?
还没完
It ain't over yet.
-不到最后就没完  -我喜欢这歌
- Ah, it's not over till it's over. - Oh, I love that song.
但疱疹也太老土了
But herpes is way too pedestrian.
要不就说得了那个新淋病吧
Maybe I'll say it's that new super gonorrhea.
我也看到消息了
Oh, yeah, I read about that.
-先生留步  -费歇尔  早
- Excuse me, sir? - Oh, Fischer. Good morning.
早  能问你一个问题吗
Good morning, sir. Do you mind if I ask you a question?
你说
Of course.
关于我们的监视
It's about our surveillance.
监控摄像头吗  都没问题
If it's about our video cameras, they all work.
你就这么对犯人们说
That's what you should tell the inmates.
不是  是电话
Oh, no, it's about our phones.
有没有谁监听犯人的通话
Do we have anyone who monitors inmate calls?
都记录在电脑上
Well, it's all recorded in a computer.
有需要我们才会听
We only review it when there's a reason.
难道不用做随机抽查吗
Don't you think we should do random check-ins?
当然要  我们抽查了
Yes. And we do.
要让他们这么觉得  不过这事不打紧
Again, they should think we do. But it's not exactly a priority.
况且有一半人都用西班牙语
And half of those conversations are in Spanish.
[西班牙语:  我的西班牙语说得可好了]
Yo hablo espanol muy bueno, sir.
喂
Hello?
利奇菲尔德女子监狱一位犯人想要联系你
An inmate from Litchfield Federal Prison is attempting to contact you.
接听  请安1
To accept this call, please press "One."
-莱瑞  -是  一切安好吗
- Larry? - Yes. Is everything all right?
都很好
Yeah. Yeah, everything's fine.
方便说话吗
Is this a good time?
方便
Of course.
我爸爸跟我说了芝加哥和关禁闭的事
My dad, he told me about Chicago and the SHU.
天哪  帕波  对不起
God, Piper, I'm so sorry.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
你确定现在方便
Are you sure that this is a good time?
我感觉你准备去哪里
It sounds like you're going somewhere.
不  我准备回家
No, no. I'm heading home.
我刚刚跟波丽在一起  我们终于吃到百吉圈了
I was with Polly. We finally had a bag-nut.
什么是百吉圈
What's a bag-nut?
就像百吉饼加甜甜圈
It's like a bagel crossed with a donut.
现在可火了
It's this big craze right now.
我们排了两小时的队
We had to wait in line for, like, two hours for it.
结果只是个加糖霜的百吉饼而已
Turns out it's a bagel with frosting on it.
我已经忘了这样挥霍自由的感觉了
I forgot what's it like to have all that freedom to waste.
是啊  我在挥霍自由
Yep. I waste my freedom,
不过我去树墩城咖啡时带了自己的杯子
but I bring my own cup to Stumptown.
帕波  你早先怎么不打电话来
Piper, why didn't you call sooner?
我们分了
We broke up?
我猜我一直都想着
And I guess I've been imagining
我能成为一个不需要依靠任何人的人
I could be this person who doesn't depend on anybody.
或者让任何人依靠我
Or lets anybody depend on me.
听到你的声音真好
It's nice to hear your voice.
Yeah, it's nice to hear your voice.
我很想你
I've missed you.
我也很想你  莱瑞
I've missed you, too, Larry.
也不是这么糟
It's not that bad.
天哪
Man!
现在不用跟人共享了
Now we don't have to share with anyone.
分离了  太好了  就是差了一点
Segregation. Awesome. Separate, but way shittier.
长远看这样更好
Well, this is better in the long run.
我们自己的浴室  我们自己做主
Our own bathroom that we control.
"淋浴时间不超过30秒"
"Showers will be limited to 30 seconds"?
靠  这么点时间我光洗下面都不够
Man, I can't even wash my twat in that amount of time.
-搞什么  维  -相信我  小姑娘
- What? Vee! - Trust me, baby girl.
我无所谓
Man, I don't care.
只要不用再排队
As long as I don't have to wait in line anymore.
要是再因为迟到被记过  我就要回紧闭室了
I get one more shot for being late, I'm back in SHU.
我他妈可受不了
I can't fucking handle that.
你迟到  我迟到
You late, I'm late.
也许黑人就是没法准时
Maybe black folk do got a problem with bein' punctual.
美味  沃森  关于你们的工作
Taystee, Watson, about your work assignments.
会有点变动
Gonna be a little change.
-她今天一岁了  -是啊
- So she's one today? - Yeah.
怎么没人带她来
Why don't nobody bring her to visit?
从马萨诸塞过来  算了吧
What, from Massachusetts? Forget it.
瞧  我说了  你男朋友就在附近真是幸运
You see, I told you you're lucky your boyfriend's so close.
她的孩子在马萨诸塞
Her kids are in Massachusetts
歌洛丽娅的孩子远在佛罗里达
and Gloria's kids is all the way in fucking Florida.
-是吗  -是的
- Really? - Yeah.
两个男孩跟姨妈一起  两个姐姐还在纽约
Two boys are with their tia. Two older girls are still in New York.
但他们不来探望
But they never visit.
-你们想看看这个吗  -好啊
- You guys wanna see this? - Yeah.
我从蜡笔上融了点蜡
All right. I got the wax from melting crayons
达娅娜画了这幅圣安东尼的画
and Dayanara drew the picture of St. Anthony.
祈祷他能给予护佑  力量和公平
You pray to him for protection and strength and justice.
为我们  也为孩子
For us and for baby.
朱莉安娜・费尔南达
Juliana-Fernanda.
-圣安东尼的神名是什么  -神名
- What's the orisha name for Saint Anthony? - Orisha?
所有的圣人不都有艺名叫什么什么神吗
You know, all the saints had, like, stage names for the booga-booga gods,
因为  那些种植园主
'cause, you know, the plantation owners,
不想再让奴隶拜神
they didn't want the slaves worshipping no more.
叫艾利谷亚
The orisha is named Eleggua.
-蜡烛芯怎么做的  -你猜
- Yo, how'd you make the wick? - I'll give you one guess.
你真的相信这个吗  真信吗
Do you really, like, believe in this? Like, for real?
-你是天主教  -是的
- You Catholic? - Yeah.
这也是天主教
Well, this is Catholic plus.
我姨妈说
Look, my tia says
无所谓对着大十字架
it doesn't matter if you're praying to a giant cross
还是小棍子祈祷
or to a itty bitty stick,
只要心存信仰就行
it's the faith that you put in it that counts.
你相信符咒  魔法什么的吗
Yeah, but do you believe in, like, spells and magic and shit?
我相信我能充分利用所能利用的
I believe I can use all the help I can get.
你要叫新人来厨房
You're getting new girls in the kitchen?
-你不能到这儿来  -你申请了吗
- You're not allowed back here. - Did you put in a request?
申请了又怎样  忙不过来就找人帮忙呗
What if I did? We need the extra help to keep up with the demand.
她让你这么做的
She put you up to this.
-她  -维
- She? - Vee.
你把话说反了  红妈
You got the scuttlebutt ass backwards, Red.
歌洛丽娅亲自去跟那个婊子说清楚了的
Gloria went in there and told that bitch what's what.
她耍你呢
She played you.
你完全不知道自己做了什么
You have no idea what you've done.
开始准备饭菜吧
We're gonna start prepping for dinner.
等等  这个不是得一直点着吗
Wait. Aren't you supposed to keep it lit?
开玩笑
You kidding?
这玩意很危险
This shit is dangerous.
不是吧  不是吧
No. No, no, no, no!
天哪  天哪  该死  该死
No! No! No, no! Fuck! Fuck!